Aadhilah Nizamdeen

Toronto, Ontario | 416-834-8301

Github: github.com/Aadhi-N/ | Portfolio: aadhilah.com

Email: <u>aadhilah.nizamdeen@gmail.com</u> | LinkedIn: <u>linkedin.com/in/aadhilahnizamdeen/</u>

OBJECTIVE

Seeking a Junior Software Developer position. Coming in with 2+ years of program, project and product management experience in the financial industry, and 1+ years as a programming hobbyist after completing coding bootcamp, with a desire to accelerate technological change in everyday daily life.

SKILLS

Technical:

- Javascript (NodeJS, React, Angular)
- HTML, CSS and tools (Babel, Webpack)
- Automated Testing methodologies & tools (Chai, Mocha)
- Databases & Data modelling (PostgreSQL, MongoDB, UML diagrams, use cases)
- Software architecture design patterns/principles & knowledge of computer science concepts

Project & Program Management:

- Methodologies: Waterfall, Agile, Scrum, Lean Six Sigma, Extreme Programming (XP)
- Tools: MS Project, JIRA, Confluence, Trello, Smartsheet, Bitbucket, Github
- User Centric Design (competitive analysis, stakeholder interviews and surveys, analytics review, user and usability testing, experience & product maps, wire-framing)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Personal Sabbatical July 2018 - Present

Moved to Los Angeles, USA for spouse's job opportunity, and after consulting with immigration lawyers, I
was not eligible to obtain a work VISA. Spent time volunteering, programming as hobby, tending to family,
traveling, reflecting. We moved back to Canada in early 2021.

Royal Bank of Canada

Community Manager

January 2017 - March 2018

- Managed and continuously designed RBC's global student tech program, and award-winning innovative incubator and accelerator labs, to create re-imagined learning and meaningful work experiences for 800+ co-op and internship students
- Executed strategic roadmaps around aggressive timelines and resource constraints, built data reporting
 capabilities and tracked early talent pipeline using a technology enterprise application created within our
 small cross-functional team of 5

Associate, RBC Career Launch Program

January 2016 - January 2017

- Associate of rotational program at RBC designed to provide targeted professional development, dedicated mentorship, and streamlined career path. My rotations included:
 - O Personal & Commercial Banking to gain in-depth understanding of company's largest business segment operations and interaction with RBC, working at the branch level
 - o RBC's local charity partner to acquire insights into nonprofit operations and their social impact within the community
 - O RBC InvestEase robo-investing service in its early stages of conception and development, aiding in product design and collaborating with multi-site project teams on technical implementation using Agile and Waterfall methodologies

Dept. of Retail and Conference Services & Dept. of Historical Cultural Studies, University of Toronto Special Events Coordinator Jan 2014 - August 2015

• Planned and organized promotional and academic events across all 3 UofT campuses, cultivating represented academic organization's growth and success in its brand and mission

Dept. of Information and Instructional Technology Services, University of Toronto

IT Student Help Desk Representative

September 2014 - May 2015

 Provided Tier 1 technical support for university students, by troubleshooting network and software issues, submitting tickets to Tier 2 support and writing procedural documentation

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

LightHouse Labs Canada

Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp

April 2018 - June 2018

Certified Associate in Project Management (CAPM)

Project Management Institute

September 2016 - September 2021

University of Toronto, Honours Bachelor of Arts

Major in Political Science and Minors in Psychology and History

September 2010 - April 2015

VOLUNTEER WORK

Minds Matter Los Angeles — Mentor

March 2019 - August 2020

Scarborough Women's Centre — Workshop Host

February 2017 - January 2018

Pathways to Education Canada — Program Facilitator

October 2015 - December 2016